Welcome back. It is time to make our
coffee mug look like a coffee mug and
not like a sad little cup. So, [gasps]
we could try to model this from our
imagination cuz like, hey, we all pick
up coffee mugs. We know what they look
like or we think we know what they look
like. Something that you learn very
quickly in 3D is that uh when you model
something from imagination, it almost
always comes out looking a little bit
funny. And the reason for that is that
your brain is very good at like
abstracting away the information that
isn't important to it. Like if you just
close your eyes right now and just think
of a doorork knob, like what does a door
do look like, right? If you had to make
one in Blender, what would it be? It's
like, okay, well, it's like a sphere
bit. You like grip it, you turn it, and
there's like a cylinder thing at the
back, and there's a cylinder that
connects it, and that's kind of that's
kind of it. But then if you were to make
that, you end up with something that
looks really basic and boring and bad
and then you go actually look at a real
doorork knob and you forget there's all
this other detail that's just not
important to your brain. Like the little
lip inside, the little hole that's on
there that so you can put a key in to
kind of like pry it open or a uh like a
a rim that kind of like cuts into it so
there's like a separate seam around it.
There's the privacy lock on the front.
all these things that just don't matter
to you when you're turning a handle and
so you forgot that they even existed
because you never even saw it really. So
the same thing applies to even something
as common as a coffee mug. So it helps
when possible to use reference images.
Now you can get reference images from
anywhere because we have the power of
the internet and you can type in
handmade coffee mug and you can pick any
mug you want to create. Um, and uh,
there's a lot. And you know, if you want
to pick one of these, if you want to
just go on Google images, uh, you can
pick one of these and and go for it. I'm
going to give you an image that I've
used. Um, but you can there's there's
some really pretty ones here. And I was,
uh, actually shocked [laughter]
just whilst like clicking on some of
these sites before, I was like, "Oh
yeah, like that's a cute cute little
handmade mug." And then you go like, "Oh
my gosh,
$123.25
and that's a discount from 145." [gasps]
And then you think like, "Oh, it must be
like a one of one like, you know, a
unique thing." Like, no, there's like
nine reviews. Like people are buying it.
I I'm like I don't know. I
[clears throat] got to make more money
or something. Like I don't know how
people are buying $123 coffee mugs. I
think it's also like we forget what
labor costs, you know, like you think
like a coffee mug is like $2, right? Or
a dollar or it's free. Like it's just
there's so many of them it doesn't even
matter. But like no, like to hand make
something like obviously any of these
mugs, they're they take more than a few
hours to make if you're making it by
hand. So like yeah, $33 is probably like
break even for them. I don't probably
not even making any [laughter] money,
but it's just like Yeah. Anyways, whole
side topic of like the economy of
handmade ceramic mugs. Um, but people
are buying them for $123.
All right. So, all that is to say is I
want you to get an image. And the one
I'm going to use, uh, the link for this
is below. Um, and uh, it's on my
website. I've got all the links to
everything we're going to be using in
this tutorial. Um, but there there's two
ways to add images. Uh, so one way is to
go to the ad menu and then just go image
and then say reference. Um, and then you
just pick wherever the reference is. Um,
and you can drop it in the alternative
way. Um, and it's something that we
didn't used to be able to do, and that's
to just, uh, drag over from wherever it
is on your computer and then just drop
it into Blender, and it will recognize
it as an image, and it will bring it in
as an image object. So, either of those
ways will work. So, this is the image.
This is the one we're going to use. Now,
if you quickly orbit around, you'll
notice that it's come in at a funny
angle. Um, now, but I don't know why
Blender does this. I think I think it's
because they they think they people want
it locked to the perspective that they
were at when they brought it in there,
but that I've [clears throat] never
needed that. So, we just need to clear
this rotation and then rotate it to the
the way we want. So, to clear the
rotation, I'm going to hit alt R. The
alternative way, object, clear rotation.
Alt R. It's the same thing. Um, now it's
flat. So, now we need to rotate it
proper upright so that it is flat on to,
you know, how it should be relative to
the scene. So, I need to rotate it. So,
I'm going to hit R. So, but we're now in
freehand rotate mode. And it's again,
it's it's relative to where we were
looking at it. Um, which is, uh, yeah,
this this funny angle. So, uh, if you
remember from before, when we're in a
move state, like rotate, scale, or grab,
uh, we can lock something to a specific
axis whilst we're in this mode by just
tapping the letter of that axis. And if
you don't know the letter, you can see
we we really want it on this red line
here. And that red top right hand corner
that is the X axis. So I'm going to hit
X. There we go. So now it is locked to
that axis which is good. And now we want
it to be 90°. So you could either hold
down control and you can see in the top
uh what that does is that's now um
moving it in 5° increments. Or you could
just type in the number 90 on your
keyboard and then hit enter. And there
we go. So that's how we bring it in and
uh clear the rotation and set it up. So,
all right. Now, it's way too big. So,
hotkey to scale something. S. Okay. S to
scale. And now I'm just going to scale
this down. And I can't see my mug. So,
my mug is behind it. So, let me just
move my mug I'll move my mug forward.
So, let's move it forward to there.
Okay. All right. And then now, um, I'm
going to look at it like front on. Okay.
So, I can do that by clicking this
little uh minus Y at the top there.
That'll do front on. or the hotkeys. Um,
because I use my numpad. For those of
you blessed with a numpad, you'll you'll
like it. You can hit numpad one, that's
front view, numpad three, that's side
view, or numpad 7, that is top view. Um,
but I use those uh a lot. But again, you
can use these if you don't have it.
Okay, so front view, and then I'm going
to scroll in to zoom. Shift middle mouse
to pan to the side. And now I'm going to
move this over here. And I'm going to
scale this down again to get it roughly
to be the size of my my mug here cuz I
know that this mug is right relative to
the donut. So, it should be good. And
then what I'm looking at um for the size
of this image here is I want the top of
this rim here to roughly match the
bottom down there. So, this like I want
that to match that. So, it's still a
little bit too big. Um and you'll notice
I can't really easily do it from this
angle. I mean I I can but the the
problem is is that this photograph is
taken with a camera from the real world
where there is perspective but we are
looking in 3D and actually when we're in
an axis like this the reason it all
becomes flattened is because it is in
perspective mode. If you click that
little button there that'll actually put
you back into perspective mode and you
can see how things get distorted and
like angles and things. So the best
reference is actually reference which is
in orthographic like blueprints for
something but you usually don't have
that. So you just go from something like
this and just kind of best guess it.
Anyways, okay, cool. So that's roughly
roughly the right size of uh of image.
Now we can model by going into uh edit
mode by hitting tab toggle in and out of
edit mode. And we can start to shape
this to look like this mug here. So the
first thing that we'll notice is like
the general broad shape of the mug is
that it actually kind of tapers towards
the top. both lines are kind of tapered
upwards. Um, and then there's like a
kind of a midpoint around about here
where it starts to invert and it goes in
the other direction. Okay. So, it's very
smooth object and perfect for using
subsurf modifier, which is what we've
already got. So, to get that taper going
up to the side, I want to shrink the top
of the mug here just a little bit. So,
I'm going to hold down alt and uh I'm
going to go into edge select mode at the
top there and then alt and then just
leftclick on that line there. Not on
like like a middle point like here or
it'll select a different edge, but just
on the middle there. And then now I want
to scale this in to just shrink the size
just a little bit. So, I'm going to
scale that to there. And then I'm going
to select the line underneath it and I'm
going to do the same thing. So, alt
click on that line, that edge, uh and
then just scale it. you know, about
halfway there. [snorts]
Now, I want to create um this like
widened point right here. And you can
see like from here, like there's there's
a lip at the bottom, but like from here
to here, and then it goes up, I'd say
probably 20% up the mug, that's where
that middle point is. So, this line is
close, but I'd probably pull it up a
little bit. So, I'm going to double tap
G, and that'll let me slide that edge
there. And I'll put it to Yeah, it's
about there. And now I want to pull it
out to make it a little bit uh a little
bit thicker. So, I'm going to hit S and
just pull that out
to about there. And now I can see this
line here is not quite right. So, I'm
going to scale this one out as well,
just a little bit. Okay, that's roughly
the right shape. Okay. Now, this bit at
the bottom here. Okay. So, I can see
already that I need a little bit more
detail. So, I'm actually going to have
to slide this line up here. So, I'm
going to hit uh double G to just kind of
slide it up. And I'm going to pull it to
about there. You can see now we've got
kind of a more curved taper on that edge
there. And I'm going to hit S to scale.
And I'm going to double tap G again.
And I'm just by eye just guessing to try
to get this form here.
Um but you can see you can very quickly
start to shape any sort of object you
want um by just moving sliding lines
around and um scaling things. Okay. So
now obviously this face at the bottom
here. So if I go into face select mode
or by just hitting three um this has to
be this little uh lip at the bottom
there. What do you call that? I guess
like a lip. It's probably a word for it.
All the all the pottery people watching
this tutorial going to tell me what it
is and they'll also tell me about the
price of manual labor and why that
coffee mug was quite well priced I'm
sure. [laughter]
Um anyways uh I'm going to yeah I'll
scale it in a little bit. I'm just
trying to guess like where would it
start? But you know you just do it by
eye. I think about there. Okay. And now
with this face here selected, I need
more geometry cuz I want to actually
pull it out from that face there. Um,
but I can't just like pull it down,
right? Cuz now it's stretching it. I
need more geometry. Um, and so that is
called an extrusion. And thankfully the
hotkey for extrusion is just the first
letter of its name, which is E. E for
extrusion. And just like inset and
everything else in Blender, the moment
you tap it, you're now in that mode. Um,
I can pull it upwards, I could pull it
downwards. Um, obviously downwards is
what we want. So, I'm going to do a
single click right there. Okay. And then
now if I go back and just look at it in
object mode. Um, and by the way, if you
want to see it like the donut, you want
to make it look uh smooth, you can as
well by going to shade smooth. Um, and
that's okay. But you can see that this
line here, this is a much tighter line.
Okay. Um, and the reason that this is
happening is of course because of
subsurf modifier um, and the way that it
works. Um, it's essentially going from
here
to here and then kind of like I guess
like a a midpoint in the middle there.
And it's trying to taper from there all
the way in. But then also from this
point here, it now has to taper from
there to kind of smooth out that line.
So we end up with just kind of like this
like very smoothed out little nub. Um,
but to fix it, we just have to add in
more geometry so that it doesn't start
the smooth so so much further up. So to
do that, we need another loop cut, which
you might remember the hotkey or you can
find it in the menu, edge, loop cut, and
slide, but it is ctrlr. So ctrlr. When
you're in this mode, where do you want
to put it first? So do a single click on
this face here. So click and then it's
now saying where do you want to slide it
to? So I'm going to slide one to the
bottom like so. And then I need another
one right above it. So, I did a click
there to confirm it. So, I'm going to
hit CtrlR. And now placing it on the
exact same place. And I'm just going to
pull it up. And there we go. And now you
can see it's much tighter at the bottom
there. Um, and it looks good. Uh, and if
you really wanted to clean up this
bottom base there, you can see we kind
of got that like starfishy pattern
happening. You could do the same thing
we did before, which is select that face
there and then do an inset. It's not
really that essential. No one's really
going to notice it, but you might. and
maybe you want to clean it up. So, yeah,
but that's pretty good. That's that's
great. That's a good start to the mug.
Um, it looks good. Awesome. Well done.
Now, it's time for the challenge of
making this handle. So, you can see it
starts about here and then obviously
extrudes around and goes back into
itself and is joined here. So, how do we
do this? So basically whenever whenever
there is a join and you can see there's
like you know like a nice like uh bevel
edge there kind of thing it has to
physically be part of the geometry of
this. You can't just have it like
existing out in in space cuz then it
won't appear to be joined together. So
essentially we have to find somewhere on
this mesh to start the handle from. Um
and that point is actually here. Right
here which is why I've modeled it this
way. Right here is where I'm going to
extrude out. Um, now before I show you
how to uh extrude, I first of all want
to show you I'm going to do something
and it's going to mess it up and I'm
going to then show you why we need to do
something else first before we start
extruding. So, if I was to extrude this
out, um, we could do the whole handle
here, get it back there, make it look
perfect, and then later on look at our
mug and go, "Oh no,
what is going on?"
The reason this happens is because of
you might remember the solidify modifier
which these modifiers they're not part
of the mesh, right? It's it's happening
after
um after the fact. So it's adding a
thickness to any mesh that we have here
and it's now adding a thickness to the
actual handle itself. So how do we fix
that? We fix that by making making this
go from a modifier to real like actually
bake it into the mesh so that it's
actually real geometry. Um, and the way
you do that is uh first of all, let me
just undo all of those. Ctrl Z, of
course. The way you do it is by going to
the modifier and then in the little drop
down in the top there, right next to
that little camera icon, there is an
apply. So when you click that, it's
disappeared. And now when you go into
edit mode though, you can see all that
geometry that wasn't there before is now
actually part of it. And you can see it
if you turn off the subsurf modifier. So
I can now make changes to the inner part
of my uh model there without it having
affecting um the rest of it. So it's
actual real uh mesh that we can we can
manipulate. Um obviously the downside is
it's no longer uh non-destructive. So
that slider that we had for changing the
thickness of the mug, we no longer have
the slider. It would just mean if we
wanted to change the thickness of the of
the mug, we would have to like do it
ourselves, like selecting all that stuff
and doing it. But that's fine. You have
to uh break uh break the workflow
eventually to add in customization. But
there you go. So anyways, now that I've
got this, now when I select this face
here, I can start to do the extrusion.
So importantly, make sure you're
selecting the right face. If you were to
select this one by mistake and then
start trying to do your handle and then
like twist it around, you it would start
to get screwed up very very quickly. So,
make sure that you've got this red line
that's like intersecting your mug there
that it is. Yeah. Like it's that one.
It's like bang on to the middle. And you
can actually check if you go into top
view mode. It should be directly in the
middle of uh of the mug there. Okay. So,
with that selected, I'm going to go into
front view mode with uh numpad one or
hitting that little uh green thing. And
then I'm going to hit again the hotkey
that we use for extrusion is E to
extrude out. Now, when you do that, it's
using the normals, the hidden um it's
like the hidden direction of each of the
faces that are on your mesh. Okay? So,
it's kind of extruding it out like that.
For most of you watching this, the
extrusion there worked perfectly. But
every now and then you go to extrude
something and it doesn't work. And it's
because there's something wrong with the
normals of the face that you tried to
extrude from. Basically, it would just
mean um you would have to clear the
normals first. So basically, you would
select the the face, then hit shift N,
and it would clear normals. I've got, by
the way, throughout this tutorial that
you're going to run into a lot of
problems that I I might not be able to
explain to you. So, I've actually
created um a troubleshooting guide
called the unstuckyour yourself guide.
So, the link for that is below as well,
but this is just like a database of all
the problems you might run into whilst
you're doing this tutorial because we
noticed um on the uh Blender Guru
Discord, link for that is below as well
where you can ask questions and share
your renders and stuff. Um a lot of
people are asking the same questions.
So, we put together this like FAQ
troubleshooting guide and um please make
use of that. So there'll probably be
when when you're modeling things, people
will run into issues. So just uh have a
look at that if you run into an issue
first. Anyways, sorry to really
painfully slowly do this, but we've
extruded out a little bit. Um now I'm
going to move this up. So just grabbing.
So G to grab. I'm going to move up. And
I might actually now I'm going to tab
out to so that I can select my image. So
I'm in object mode. And I'm actually
just going to move this over. So G and
then X. move it over to be about there.
Okay.
And that'll just enable me to kind of
see relative to to the mug where it
should go. Like what is the shape? I
could do it by eye, but yeah, I figure
might as well just it's right there.
Might as well just grab it and pull it
over. So, um I need to position this
about here, but you can see it's kind of
getting like skewed, right? Um and that
is because it's uh it's obviously coming
in at like a like this slanted angle.
So, with that face selected, um, I need
to rotate it. So, I'm going to hit R to
rotate. Like so. Okay. So, like that.
All right. And I might
Just trying to think. All right. I
definitely need a loop cut because
obviously that bit that's coming out
looking like a knob on our mug there.
So, I'm going to hit CtrlR to create a
loop cut. And I'm going to pull it down
just so that I can see it's like where
where it should join basically at the
base there. All right. Great. And now
face select mode. Select that face
again. And now we just have to keep
extruding around. But what I want to do
is I want to scale. Just make the handle
look a little bit thinner. So I'm going
to select this top edge here. And I'm
going to double tap G just so that I can
slide it downwards a little bit to just
make it a little bit thinner cuz that
handle obviously doesn't look as as fat
as uh as what we had there. So all
right. So face select mode now. And now
I'm going to start to extrude. So
another extrusion. G to reposition. R to
rotate it. And I just want to rotate it
so that it kind of follows the contours
of uh of this. So I'm going to be
rotating it like this kind of angle as
we go around. So now E to do another
extrusion. Click. G. Click. R.
Now, by the way, there is another way to
extrude which is actually kind of
perfect for this. Um, but if you hold
down control and then rightclick, it
will not only extrude, but it will also
rotate the faces so that they align. And
it can be a little helpful um, a bit
more easier than doing this like E, G,
R, S, G, R, like, so just holding down
control and then rightclick
will just place these little points um,
and will rotate them so that you don't
have to do all that rotation yourself.
It really only works for these kind of
appendages like this, but might as well
use it because it's a very um handy way
to do it. Okay, cool. So, now now the
tricky bit. It's not really that tricky.
It's it's relatively easy to solve, but
it's it's a conundrum, right? Like how
do we make this mesh with the rest of
the mesh? Um, and you do that by like
the wrong way to do this would be to
just like kind of like smush them
together, right? And this is kind of
like early 3D stuff. like a lot of stuff
was like this. This kind of mashed stuff
and intersected it together, but then
you don't get that edge there where it
like catches the light. And the only way
to really get that is to actually
physically like join this mesh together.
So this face here has to be connected to
this face somehow. Um and the easiest
way in this case to do is to first of
all we can see that this line here is
like cutting into the middle of this uh
this this copy, right? So, we really
need to just add a line that goes around
there to make this this area here like
one face to match um this sorry this
this this handle. So, I'm going to add
that line by hitting CtrlR loop cut
click and then I'm going to slide it up
to be you know roughly about there.
That's fine. And then now um because
I've intersected it that that went too
far. Um so I'm holding down Z. Um, now
this is a way of quickly changing the
mode that you're you're viewing
something in. Um, and we'll we'll get to
these other two once we get to materials
rendering and stuff, but for now, if you
just swap to wireframe mode, this will
show you through the mesh. Um, there is
another way to see through a mesh, and
that is to at the top there, that little
X-ray or alt Z is a hotkey for it. Um,
but that's that's another way to do it.
Um, but yeah, that you can see that's
that's wireframe. And then, oh, hang on
a second. Nope, that's that's X-ray.
This is wireframe. But yeah, they're
they're are they're pretty similar.
Anyways, so I'm gonna select my my face
here and I'm just going to pull it out
just so that I can just just grab it
basically. And now I can go back to my
solid view as before. Okay, so I touched
on this briefly before, but like a mesh
is made up of these individual points,
right? This is what you're seeing when
you're in uh verticy mode, these
individual points. Um and each of those
points when you have four together,
three or more actually, um you can
create a face. Um and so that's what
that is. So essentially I need to create
a new face for this section right here.
So let's do that now. So I'm going to
select those two and I've just selected
them by holding down uh shift like this.
And then I'm just going to hit F. Face.
Okay. And then I can do the same on this
side
like that. And then I'm going to do the
same on the top.
And then I'm going to do the same
underneath.
Okay. All right. So I've done it. But
and I did it deliberately this way
because I need to show you um the the
reason for this this issue here. So
we've got yeah we we've we've got the
faces so they should be going smoothly
across here. But because of the way
meshes work and the way they try to
sorry the way shoot uh smooth shading
works is it does it based on like a
continuous flow of faces. And you will
have noticed that when we created this
there was actually a face that is inside
here before we joined it. Okay, which
and I'll I'll show you. If we go into
here, this area here, you should see
there is a face that is right here. So,
because that exists, the smooth shader
doesn't actually know that it's supposed
to continue on because there's a face
that goes down. So, it's now kind of
mixed. It doesn't know like it has to
create a smooth shading here, but then
also one on the top there. And so, it's
done this weird um hybrid thing where
it's like it's tried to do it, but
there's clearly something going on
underneath. So, what we need to do is
just delete that face. So, again, in
face select mode, you select that inner
face there. And by the way, when you're
working in 3D, this is a really common
thing beginners do. They select the
wrong face. So, you can see how quickly
that like they're right next to each
other, that point there, right? But
selecting one or the other, it it just
happens all the time. So, a thing that a
lot of 3D artists do is when they've
selected something before they delete
it, you just do a quick orbit around and
that'll just like break the perspective
and just to verify that that is the
actual one I mean to select. Okay. Then
I'm going to hit X and I'm going to say
faces. Okay. But it's not just that one,
right? Like that. Actually, that that
should be fixed soon, but anyway, I'll
show you how. Um, and then there's one
on the inside here as well. Okay. Cuz
when we joined it, there was there was a
face here and there was a face over
there. So I'm now going to delete that
face by hitting X and then say faces.
Okay, now that's done.
This should be correct. But the reason
it's not is one I think if I need to
right click and say shade smooth and
that has fixed it. What on what can
happen sometimes is when you've fixed up
some geometry um you might need to uh
recalculate the normals like which and
again to bring up the normals there's a
secret hidden line uh that every face on
your your object has and they're always
pointing outward like that. But when
you've created new mesh and you've kind
of fix things or whatnot, you can end up
with one of these lines that goes the
wrong direction. Um and I'll show you
that actually if I just do this.
um that's what it might look like. You
get this weird like black shading
artifacts. Um that's very ugly. So to
fix that, you select your entire mesh
and then you hit shift N and that will
recalculate it. Um and now you can see
the smooth shading is correct. And just
to show you quickly as well, um the way
I did it just then where we like created
it and then we deleted the faces. Don't
do this. I'm just going to show you like
actually what you would do cuz it's not
this tedious. Normally, if you had this
problem, you would actually select this
face and this face first. You delete
them ahead of time and then actually,
and there's a faster way to have uh
created this this join here. Um you can
select that entire edge loop with alt
then shift alt select that. And now I
could rightclick and say bridge edge
loops, which you only can do if you've
got the exact same number of uh vertices
on one side as the other. But I want to
just show you physically creating those
points with uh vertices cuz that is a
really common way to to model to join
things together. You select the four
vertices, you create a new face.
Anyways, look at that. We've got what
looks like a handle coming out of the
mug. Now, if we look at our reference
here, um we've got it pretty close, but
you can see that there's like it's
sharp, right? There's there's clearly
like a crease here and a crease here.
Um, and we can do that just by adding in
more loop cuts. So, I'm going to add in
uh well, I guess there's two ways to do
it. One, I can actually just select this
edge here. So, holding down alt, just
select that and then double tap G and I
can bring that in. Um, but when I do
that, this area becomes a little bit
straight. Um, maybe not what I wanted.
Let's have a look at front mode. Um,
yeah, I might want a little bit more
detail there, which case I would add a
loop cut. Um, but you know, it's really
up to you. You might be able to just,
you know, move this around and just kind
of shape it. Like, look, we're really
we're learning Blender. That's really
the [laughter] goal of this. It's not
necessarily to make a physically
accurate uh mug. I don't want to over
complicate things and make things feel
like you have to do everything
perfectly, but I also don't want to end
up with like a trash result and then
everyone be like, "Oh, we did all that
effort and now it looks garbage." Um,
but you know, you could spend a lot of
effort. You know, you could even try and
get like if you look at, you know, uh
there would be probably like a little
line here like like the kind of, you
know what I mean? Like on the inner
inner part of the the thing, you could
try and create that. You could really
add a lot of detail. The only thing I'm
really going to fix is right here where
it's pinching. I'm just going to select
that edge there and I'm going to double
tap G. I'm just going to slide it up so
there's just a little less pinching. And
then this part here like you can see the
shape of this face is being very
distorted. Right? You generally want to
keep things as close to a squareish
shape as possible generally. Um and so
I'm just going to select this edge at
the bottom there. Double tap G. And I'm
just going to pull it out just to
relieve a little bit of the the tension
there. And
I mean that's I mean you can Yeah,
there's obviously there's like a tighter
line there but this will do. this this
is enough to be uh perceived as a coffee
mug. Now, if you want to just move ahead
with the tutorial and get on to the next
part, which is going to be on uh
materials and lighting, um you can you
can do that. However, if you want a
little bit of a challenge, like a little
bit of a homework, um where you can try
to use some skills but by yourself, you
will see looking at the photo here that
we also have a saucer, a little tiny
plate for our mug. Um, now I didn't
include that in my final image. Um, I
just had the coffee mug just sitting on
the table. Um, but this is a great very
small thing that you could try to model
by yourself using the skills that you've
just learned um to to create something
new. So, how would you go about adding
that saucer? You could have a have a try
at it. It it's a completely separate
object obviously to your mug here. So,
even if you screw it up, worst case
scenario is you just delete it and then,
you know, you'll still end up with
something that I actually had for my
final result, which was a mug without a
saucer. But, if you want to add that in,
it'll be a way to kind of take some of
the lessons that you've uh you've you've
picked up already and then try to
remember them and the different steps
and the things um required to create it.
Because whilst you've just created
something now, it's the best time to try
to recall that memory so that in the
future, maybe in a few days or a few
weeks from now, when you try to do
something yourself, it'll be a lot more
readily available to recall that
information. So, if you want to have a
go at doing that, uh, feel free to.
Otherwise, join me in the next part and
we'll get on to some materials and
texturing.